<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on James Hughes</title>
    <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/categories/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on James Hughes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 09:02:12 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.jimdhughes.com/categories/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating my Blog from Ghost to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2020/migrating-my-blog-from-ghost-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 09:02:12 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2020/migrating-my-blog-from-ghost-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>For Canada Day, I decided to migrate my blog from Ghost to Hugo. I have sort-of reasons that I&amp;#39;ll discuss here but ultimately, I was just bored of my current setup and figured I could save a few bucks a month in hosting fees by using github to host my static content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Go - Morse Code!</title>
      <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/morse-code-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 02:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/morse-code-in-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was watching Churchill&amp;rsquo;s secret agents on Netflix the other day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all of a sudden I got a hit of nostalgia when they got to the portion on morse code.  Such an ingenious little method of communcation that I still, to this day, couldn&amp;rsquo;t follow for the life of me!
I took a class on encryption and one of the first concepts they spoke of was morse code.  Taking language and transcribing it into a not-so-easy to decipher combination of beeps and blips to send messages over a wire.&lt;br&gt;
Some other fun facts for those of you that haven&amp;rsquo;t taken any introductory encryption classes, morse code is designed very closely following a common english language frequency table.  That is, a table that determines the frequency at which a letter appears in the alphabet.  Letters that appear frequently are, in morse code, encoded using fewer and shorter . and -&amp;rsquo;s!
I&amp;rsquo;ve added in a column to the table found at:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pi.math.cornell.edu/~mec/2003-2004/cryptography/subs/frequencies.html&#34;&gt;http://pi.math.cornell.edu/~mec/2003-2004/cryptography/subs/frequencies.html&lt;/a&gt;
and put in the morse code equilvalent for a quick reference&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
