<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on James Hughes</title>
    <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on James Hughes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 05:29:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.jimdhughes.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I got my PMP! With other random thoughts.</title>
      <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/i-got-my-pmp-with-other-random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 05:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/i-got-my-pmp-with-other-random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FINALLY!
I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned it in previous articles but I&amp;rsquo;ve finally done it.  I got my PMP.
The whole process really highlighted a few personality traits that I&amp;rsquo;ve developed at recently in my life.  They&amp;rsquo;re essentially as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pursue so many things in an effort to claim that I&amp;rsquo;m too busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hate.. &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; failing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have too many ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since starting down my career path, I&amp;rsquo;ve made some massive changes to my demeanour. I used to be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; technical.  I wanted to be extremely proficient in &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; thing.  I thought that this would be what sets me apart and what makes me indispensable.  I&amp;rsquo;m now about 7 years in and I&amp;rsquo;ve taken such a drastic turn that I had to look back hard to determine where it happened and why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;Thoughts&gt; Print vs Media - Hoof</title>
      <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/thought-how-im-anti-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/thought-how-im-anti-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TLDR;
I learned to memorize by reading and writing paper content
I learned to look up using digital content.
I find myself continually using indexing and ctrl-f to find information in digital content whereas I actually read and commit to memory when I read physical text and write physical notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lessons I learned once and apparently have forgotten since&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep. Awkward, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m studying for my PMP exam (finally) and up until now I&amp;rsquo;ve been using PDF&amp;rsquo;s and the like to read and jot down notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;Thoughts&gt; Keeping Myself Organized</title>
      <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/thoughts-keeping-myself-organized/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2018/thoughts-keeping-myself-organized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-most-productive-months-through-2017&#34;&gt;My most productive months through 2017&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were from about July through to the middle of December.  As I sit here in my office I wonder what happened?
I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from completing &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;actionable&lt;/strong&gt; items daily to feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m just spinning my tires again, but I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not. Since my first day back to work of 2018, I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a prototype for a potential new internal project
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furthermore I&amp;rsquo;ve had 1 sit-down meeting to demo the application sprints and 3 meaningful conversations around alignment of the processes we&amp;rsquo;re looking to automate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a mind map for implementing some new corporate infrastructure and initiated conversation with my company&amp;rsquo;s operations team
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a fair bit of background fact-finding which date back to December of last year to be fair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consolidated 10 years of data from excel workbooks to transcribe into a newly developed application&amp;rsquo;s database (specifically for the first bullet point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitted the paperwork to sit for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://pmi.org&#34;&gt;PMP&lt;/a&gt; examination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good amount of work for 10 days back at it I think? So why do I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m not actually accomplishing anything?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Huzzah to Millennials killing everything - By a Millennial</title>
      <link>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2017/a-huzzah-to-millennials-killing-everything-by-a-millennial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 21:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jimdhughes.com/posts/2017/a-huzzah-to-millennials-killing-everything-by-a-millennial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had an article pushed to me by LinkedIn from Business Insider titled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Psychologically scarred&amp;rsquo; millennials are killing countless industries from napkins to Applebee&amp;rsquo;s — here are the businesses they like the least&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to go through their list and put a bit of dialogue around a Canadian&amp;rsquo;s perspective on all these alleged failures. (Yep, Dialogue. We have French in our English). You can see the original article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/millennials-are-killing-list-2017-8/#casual-dining-chains-like-buffalo-wild-wings-and-applebees-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-casual-dining-chains&#34;&gt;1. Casual Dining Chains&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article references Applebee&amp;rsquo;s. I&amp;rsquo;ve personally &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; been to Applebee&amp;rsquo;s so I&amp;rsquo;m going to reference a chain that I used to go to all the time - Boston Pizza.
For me to get a Bandera Pizza Bread at Boston Pizza, I can expect to pay $11.50 for Bandera Pizza Bread - a delightful treat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
