<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>technology on James Hughes</title><link>/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on James Hughes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2020 James Hughes.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:15:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>&lt;Thoughts> Print vs Media - Hoof</title><link>/posts/2018/thought-how-im-anti-tech/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:15:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018/thought-how-im-anti-tech/</guid><description>TLDR; I learned to memorize by reading and writing paper content I learned to look up using digital content. I find myself continually using indexing and ctrl-f to find information in digital content whereas I actually read and commit to memory when I read physical text and write physical notes.
Lessons I learned once and apparently have forgotten since
Yep. Awkward, right?
Hear me out.
I&amp;rsquo;m studying for my PMP exam (finally) and up until now I&amp;rsquo;ve been using PDF&amp;rsquo;s and the like to read and jot down notes.</description></item><item><title>&lt;Thoughts> Keeping Myself Organized</title><link>/posts/2018/thoughts-keeping-myself-organized/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 02:11:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018/thoughts-keeping-myself-organized/</guid><description>My most productive months through 2017 Were from about July through to the middle of December. As I sit here in my office I wonder what happened? I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from completing real actionable items daily to feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m just spinning my tires again, but I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not. Since my first day back to work of 2018, I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully:
Implemented a prototype for a potential new internal project Furthermore I&amp;rsquo;ve had 1 sit-down meeting to demo the application sprints and 3 meaningful conversations around alignment of the processes we&amp;rsquo;re looking to automate.</description></item></channel></rss>