<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>ReactJS on James Hughes</title><link>/categories/reactjs/</link><description>Recent content in ReactJS on James Hughes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2020 James Hughes.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 13:07:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/reactjs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IndexedDB + React for Offline Storage</title><link>/indexeddb-react/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 13:07:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/indexeddb-react/</guid><description>Offline data is annoying.
I&amp;rsquo;m used to storing data in localstorage which is okay&amp;hellip; sometimes. When you have a small amount of data to store such as user settings or persisting filters between views then this is a decent enough solution. I was working on a project recently that had a wild requirement appear where we needed to store upwards of 10k items offline. Needless to say, this put performance problems in our application.</description></item><item><title>Fetching data with react</title><link>/fetching-data-with-react/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 02:37:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fetching-data-with-react/</guid><description>What use is an app that can&amp;rsquo;t persist data?
I&amp;rsquo;m continuing this from my previous post about my efforts to learn about react. I want to be able to persist my data on a server and display it on a web client. To my understanding, this should be pretty simple so I&amp;rsquo;m going to put that theory to the test.
Firstly! We&amp;rsquo;re going to use a Node.js scaffold that I covered off in a previous posting as our backend for this app.</description></item><item><title>Learning React with create-react-app</title><link>/learning-react-with-create-react-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 20:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/learning-react-with-create-react-app/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an Angular kind of guy.
I&amp;rsquo;ve built several front end applications using Angular 1.x and 2+. I&amp;rsquo;ve built hybrid mobile apps using the Ionic Framework. In this time, I seem to have just completely ignored the phenomenon that is React js. There are so many frameworks that I&amp;rsquo;ve not even touched but if any of the job postings I&amp;rsquo;m seeing are an indication, the appetite for React and React Native developers is increasing rapidly.</description></item></channel></rss>